Andrew Ellicott Douglass papers, 1867-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Tree-Ring Materials, 1894-1966
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter IV, drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter V, drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter VI, drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): chapter VII, drafts and discards. 1936 (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): preliminary illustrations. 1936 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): first draft. 1936 (Box 112, Folder 2-4)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): "Copy X." 1936 (Box 112, Folder 5-6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): "Old Text." 1936 (Box 113, Folder 1-3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): "Old Text Corrected," by A.E.D. and W.S. Glock. 1936 (Box 113, Folder 4-5)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): illustration lists. 1936 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): test cyplots...used for volume three. 1936 (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): final re-typed copy. 1936 (Box 114, Folder 1-3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): copy as used by printer. 1936 (Box 114, Folder 4-6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): first galley. 1936 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): second galley. 1936 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): page proof (incomplete). 1936 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): correspondence. October 1935-July 1936 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): correspondence. August 1936-July 1937, 1943 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): original photographs. 1936 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): copy of volume as published (three copies). 1936 (Box 115)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume three): original illustrations. 1936 (Box 116)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): correspondene (miscellaneous) (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): drafts and discards, preliminary material, parts I-II. (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): drafts and discards, parts III-IV, appendix. (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): pages extrated from A.E.D.'s copy, substitutions made. (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): A.E.D.'s copy. (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): press copy with press corrections. (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): correspondence and work of Mary (Douglass) Rackliffe on manuscript. (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): illustrations. (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Climatic Cycles and Tree Growth (volume four, unfinished): original illustrations. (Box 118)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: Astronomy articles. 1903-1936 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: Religion and Ethics articles. 1895-1918 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "The Scientific Basis of Religion." 1924 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: miscellaneous articles. 1894-1948 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: mailing lists for A.E.D.'s publications. (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Weather Cycles in the Growth of Trees," (published in the Monthly Weather Review, no.37). 1909 (Box 120, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "An Optical Periodograph," (published in Astrophysical Journal, vol.41, no.3). April 1915 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Climatic Recoeds in the Trunks of Trees," (published in American Forestry, vol.23, no.288). December 1917 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: Science Service Article. 1921 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Dating our Prehistoric Ruins," (published in Natural History, vol.21, no.1). January/Febuary 1921 (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: miscellaneous articles. 1900-1928 (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "The Secret of the Southwest Solved by Talkative Tree Rings," (published in the National Geographic Magazine, vol.56, no. 6). December 1926 (Box 121, Folder 1-3)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Tree Growth and Solar Cycles," (published in the Third Report of the Commission Apponted to Further the Study of Solar and Terrestrial Relationships, International Research Council). 1931 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Trees and Droughts in Arizona," (published in the Professional Engineer, vol.16, no.6). June/July 1931 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Climatic Interpretation of Tree Growth," (originally titled "Tree Rings and Climate," and written for the Journal of the Royal Geographical Society in 1930. Re-written, but not published). 1932 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Tree Rings and Climate: Illustrated Summary." 1933 (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: miscellaneous articles. 1929-1934 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Estimated Ring Chronology," (notes, charts, and some text for the series of articles with this title that appeared in the Tree Ring Bulletin). 1935-1940 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "The Central Pueblo Chronology," (published in the Tree Ring Bulletin, vol.2, no.4). April 1936 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "tree Rings and Climatic Cycles," (originally written in 1938 for American Scholar, but not published. Re-written and eventually published in the Phi Kappa Phi Journal, vol.24, no.3). September 1944 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Crossdating the Ring Sequences of Trees." 1939 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Crossdating in Dendrochronology," (published in the Journal of Forestry, vol.39, no.10). October 1941 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Crossdating at Mesa Verde National Park," (published in the Journal of Forestry, vol.40, no.4). April 1942 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Notes on the Technique of Tree Ring Analysis," (drafts of various parts of a series with this title that appeared in the Tree Ring Bulletin). 1940-1943 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: miscellaneous articles. 1935-1944 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Survey of Sequoia Studies, I-II," (published in the Tree Ring Bulletin, vol.11, no.4 and vol.12, no.2). 1945 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Sequoia Survey, III," (published in the Tree Ring Bulletin, vol.13, no.1). July 1946 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Precision of Ring Dating in Tree-Ring Chronologies," (published in the University of Arizona Bulletin, vol.17, no.3 and Laboratory of Tree Ring Research Bulletin, no.3). July 1946 (Box 123, Folder 3-4)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Introduction to an Astro-Climatic Hypothesis Dealing with Periods Longer than the Year." 1953 (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: Brief Survey of an Astro-Climatic Hypothesis." 1955 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: miscellaneous articles. 1945-1960 (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Climatic Cycles in the Southwestern United States." (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Dating Pueblo Bonito and otaher Ruins of the Southwest," (drafts). 1930-1934 (Box 124, Folder 1-4)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Dating Pueblo Bonito and otaher Ruins of the Southwest," (as published by the National Geographic Society). 1935 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Dating Pueblo Bonito and otaher Ruins of the Southwest," (correspondence). 1935 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Articles by A.E.D.: "Dating Pueblo Bonito and otaher Ruins of the Southwest," (original illustrations). 1935 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: Astronomical and Astrophysical Society of America (Harvard College Observatory). August 1910 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: Internationa Union for Co-operation in Solar Research, 4th Conference (Mt. Wilson). August 29-September 6, 1910 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: Astronomical and Astrophysical Society of America (12-14th meetings). 1911-1912 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 18th meeting (with the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1st Pacific Coast Division meeting, San Francisco and Berkeley). August 2-7, 1915 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: Second Pan-American Scientific Congress (A.E.D.'s address, "The Callendar Sunshine Recorder and Some of the World-wide Problems to which this Instrument can be Applied"). December 27, 1915-January 8, 1916 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 21st meeting (Dudley Observatory, Albany, NY). August 29-September 1, 1917 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 22nd meeting (Harvard College Observatory). August 20-23, 1918 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Association for the Advancement of Science, Pacific Division (Pasadena, California). June 19-22, 1919 (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 23rd meeting (University of Michigan, Ann Arbor). September 2-5, 1919 (Box 125, Folder 9)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Association for the Advancement of Science, 72nd meeting (St. Louis). December 29, 1919-January 3, 1920 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Asronomical Society, 24th meeting (Smith College, Northhampton, MA.). September 1-4, 1920 (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - Scientific Meetings attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 25th meeting (University of Chicago). December 28-30, 1920 (Box 125, Folder 12)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Associaito for the Advancement of Science, 73rd meeting (Chicago). December 27, 1920-January 1, 1921 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Conference on Weather Forecasting (San Francisco). February 1911 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: "American Philosophical Society, general meeting (Philapelphia). April 20-22, 1922 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 28th meeting (Yerkes Observatory, Williams Bay, Wisconsin, A.E.D.'s address, "The Steward Observatory of the University of Arizona). September 5-8, 1922 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: 1st Conference of Cycles (Carnegie Institution, Washington, D.C., A.E.D.'s papers "Conclusions from Tree-Ring Data" and "General Methods in the Advance of Cycle Studies.") December 8-9, 1922 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Association for the Advancement of Science, 76th meeting (Boston). December 26-30, 1922 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Association for the Advancement of Science, 77th meeting (Los Angeles). September 17-20, 1923 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 31st meeting (Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY). December 27-29, 1923 (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Meteorological Society and the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, affiliated societies meeting at the A.A.A.S., Pacific Division's 8th meeting (Stanford University, Palo Alto). June 25-28, 1924 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 33rd meeting (Washington, D.C.). December 29, 1924-January 3, 1925 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Meteorological Society and the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, affiliated societies meeting at the AAAS., Pacific Division's 9th meeting (Portland, Oregon). June 17-20, 1925 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Association for the Advancement of Science, 82nd meeting (Kansas City). December 28, 1925-January 2, 1926 (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 37th meeting (Philadelphia). December 26-28, 1926 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: 2nd Conference on Cycles (Carnegie Institution, Washington, D.C.). December 15, 1928 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 41st meeting. December 27, 1928-January 2, 1929 (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Report on the Conferences on Cycles, published by Carnegie Institution of Washington, D.C. 1929 (Box 127)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Association for the Advancement of Science, Pacific Division, 14th meeting (Eugene, Oregon). June 18-20, 1930 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: International Union of Geodesy and Geophysics, 4th general assembly (Stockholm). August 14-23, 1930 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: British Associatio for hte Advancement of Science, 100th year (Bristol). September 3-10, 1930 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Correspondence, passport, voyage. 1930 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Travel brochures and guides (Scandinavia, Paris, New York). 1930 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Diary and notes. June-September 1930 (Box 128)
  - Printed booklets: Nordiska Museet: The Historical and Ethnographical Department of Skansen: A short guide for the use of visitors, by Axel Nilsson and Nils Keyland, 5th edition, Stockholm. 1923 (Box 128)
  - Nordiska Museeet: Skansens Kulturgeschichtliche Abteilung, by Fuhrer von Sigurd Erixon, 2.Auf1, Stockholm. 1930 (Box 128)
  - National Historical Museum: A brief guide to the collections of prehistoric and mediaeval antiquities, Stockholm. 1930 (Box 128)
  - Svenska Turisttrafikfurbundet: A book about Sweden, by Gustav Asbrink, third edition, Stockholm. 1928 (Box 128)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: National Academy of Sciences, Annual Meeting (Washington, D.C.). April 25-27, 1932 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: "Evidences of Cycles in Tree Ring Records," (various drafts, revisions, notes, correspondence, illustrations, etc.). 1932-1935 (Box 129, Folder 2-4)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Cycle Conference (California). August 1935 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: 3rd Conference on Cycles (Carnegie Institution, Washington, D.C.). April 23-25, 1937 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: U.S. Department of Agriculture Conference on Man and Nature in the Great Plains and the Arid Southwest (Flagstaff, Arizona). September 4-5, 1939 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Meteorological Society Meeting (SLC, Utah). June 15-20, 1942 (Box 130, Folder 3-5)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: American Astronomical Society, 82nd meeting (Tucson, AZ). December 28-31, 1949 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Conference on Planetary Atmospheres (Lowell Observatory, Flagstaff, AZ). August 22-24, 1951 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Scientific Meetings Attended by A.E.D.: Conference on Solar Energy (Tucson, AZ). October 31-November 1, 1955 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: Organization, and Executive Committee Papers. 1919-1920 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: Executive Committee Papers and miscellaneous papers. 1921-1943 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: correspondence regarding national monuments. 1920-1922 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 1st Annual Meeting. December 2-4, 1920 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 2nd Annual Meeting. January 26-28, 1922 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: "Some Aspects of the Use of the Annual Rings of Trees in Climatic Study," (drafts, correspondence, etc., published in Scientific Monthly, vol.15, no.1. Reprinted in the Smithsonian Report for 1922. Abstract published in Science, vol.55, no. 1429). 1922 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 2nd Annual Meeting (Santa Fe), "The 36-inch Reflector of the Steward Observatory, University of Arizona," "Note about the White Spot on Mars, July 9-10, 1922," and "Recent Studies upon Cycles in Tree Growth." September 6-9, 1922 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 4th Annual Meeting (Los Angeles). September 17-20, 1923 (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 5th Annual Meeting (El Paso), "University of Arizona Eclipse Pictures, September 10, 1923, at Port Libertad, Mexico," "The Different Focal Combinations of the Steward Observatory 36-inch Reflector," and "Two Astronomical Notes: Fernando Sanford's Electrical Inductionof the Sun on the Earth, and MacWilliam's Cosmic Evolution." May 5-7, 1924 (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 6th Annual Meeting (Boulder, CO), "A Method of Photographing Shadow Bands at a Total Eclipse," and "Note on the Study of the Planet Matrs in an Opposition of 1924." June 9-11, 1925 (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 7th Annual Meeting (Phoenix), "Infra-Red Photographs of Mars and Its Atmosphere," "Interpretation of Unwritten History: the Beginnings of Science," "Terrestrial Response to Solar Radiation," and "Radio Time Distribution." February 15-18, 1926 (Box 131, Folder 11)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: Abstracts of papers, Physical Science Section, given at the 7th annual meeting in Phoenix. February 15-18, 1926 (Box 131, Folder 12)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 8th Annual Meeting (Santa Fe), "Cycles in Southwestern Trees," and "Knowing the Southwest." April 12-14, 1927 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 9th Annual Meeting (Flagstaff, AZ) and 10th Annual Meeting (Albuquerque, NM), "The Cyclograph." April 23-26, 1928, April 22-25, 1929 (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 11th Annual Meeting (Tucson, AZ), "Solar-Terrestrial Relations." April 21-25, 1930 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 12-13, 15-17, and 20th Annual Meetings. 1930-1940 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: "Tree Rings and Chronology," (outline, early drafts, lecture as given). 1937 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: "Tree Rings and Chronology," (later versions and revisions in preparation for publication). 1937 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: "Tree Rings and Chronology," (Galleys, page proof, and copy as published in the University of Arizona Bulletin, vol.8, no.4, and Physical Science Bulletin, no.1). October 1937 (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division: 26th Annual Meeting (Flagstaff), "Tree Ring Hydrology of the Missouri River Basin," (written by Edmund Schulman, read by A.E.D.). April 30-May 4, 1950 (Box 132, Folder 8)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in box). 1906-1915 (Box 133)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in box). 1915-1922 (Box 134)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1923-1924 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Evolution from the Viewpoint of an Astronomer," (Congregational Church, Tucson, AZ). February 10, 1924 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Lectures & Addresses: Phi Kappa Phi Installation Address (University of Southern California, Los Angeles; published in Phi Kappa Phi Journal, December 1925 and October 1926). June 14, 1924 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1924-1925 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Cycles in Development of Tree Rings as an Evidence of Climatic Variation," (Carnegie Institution, Washington, D.C.). December 5, 1924 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1925-1926 (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1926-1927 (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Two Sciences," (commencement address, Norther Arizona State Teachers College, Flagstaff, AZ, published in Atlantic Monthly, October 1927). December 17, 1926 (Box 135, Folder 8)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1927-1928 (Box 135, Folder 9)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1928-1929 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1929-1930 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Science and Human Welfare," (Liberal Arts Lecture, University of Arizona). November 5, 1929 (Box 136, Folder 3-4)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1930-1931 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1931-1932 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Tree Rings and Their Relation to Solar Varioations and Chronology," (research award address, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.). December 18, 1931 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Lectures & Addresses: Research Corporation Award (includes clippings, photos, placque, published account of the presentation and text of addresses). (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1932-1933 (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Tree Growth and Climatic Cycles," (Carnegie Institution, Washington, D.C.; published in Scientific Monthly, December 1933; reprinted in Carnegie Institution Supplementary Publication no.9, July 1934). December 2, 1932 (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1934-1935 (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Tree Rings and Climate," (Radio Talk, KVOA, Tucson, AZ). January 5, 1934 (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1934-1935 (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Cycles and Tree Growth in Arizona," (Radio Talk, KGAR, Tucson, AZ). February 20, 1935 (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1935-1936 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1936-1937 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1937-1941 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Tree Rings and Climatic Cycles," (Association of Western Engineers, Phoenix, AZ). December 8, 1938 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Dendrochronology and Studies in Cyclics," (University of Pennsylvania Bicentennial Conference, Philadelphia). September 1940 (Box 138, Folder 5-6)
  - Lectures & Addresses: University of Pennsylvania Bicentennial Conference (correspondence). (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Lectures & Addresses: University of Pennsylvania Bicentennial Conference (programs, clippings, etc). September 1940 (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Lectures & Addresses (itemized list in folder). 1941-1943 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Unlimited Horizons," (NBC Radio Series). 1942 (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Recent Advances in Dendrochronology," (50th Anniversary of the Arizona State Museum). April 7, 1943 (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - Lectures & Addresses: "Seven Keys to the Vaults of Heaven," (Lecture on star identification for the Naval Indoctrination School, University of Arizona). April 26, 1943 (Box 139, Folder 4)